JAIMIN MARFATIA

Marfatiajaimin@gmail.com · (+1) 647-739-1224 · Website: https://jaimin-marfatia.github.io

Accomplished Software Engineer with over 6 years of Professional Software Development experience building applications using Microsoft Technologies. Keen to learn new technologies and implement them to gain better efficiency in application.

EXPERIENCE

APRIL 2018 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ELECTIONS ONTARIO

- Working within an Agile development environment using Microsoft technologies
- Solid and creative contributions towards analysis and design
- Adapting and quickly developing an in-depth technical understanding of new/different applications, and complex technology frameworks
- Translate application storyboards and use cases into functional applications
- Knack for writing clean, readable C# code
- Hands on experience with pair programming and mentoring/assisting colleagues
- Environment C#, ASP.NET Web API, .NET Core, Angular 5, Visual Studio 2017 & 2019, VSTS, Azure DevOps, MS SQL Server 2016

MARCH 2014 - APRIL 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, AMAZING PRINT CORPORATION

- Programming for new development, support, and maintenance of existing systems
- Involved in coding for business and data access components for key modules
- Maintained monthly timesheet for project progress tracking and weekly task assignment work sheet
- Used Microsoft Team Foundation Server (TFS) as well as SVN for the source code and version control of the files and the project
- Environment C#, ASP.NET, Visual Studio 2012 and 2013, Microsoft Team Foundation Server, MS SQL Server 2008 and 2014, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, LINQ, Ajax, XML, Json

SKILLS

- Core Programming Languages C#, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API
- Front-End Technologies HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular, TypeScript
- Databases SQL, MS SQL Server 2008, 2012, 2016
- Version Control TFS, VSTS/Azure DevOps
- Cloud Technologies Microsoft Azure
- Possess significant knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Development Methodologies Kanban, AGILE

• GitHub Profile - https://github.com/jaimin-marfatia

TECHNICAL CERTIFICATIONS

- MTA (Microsoft Technology Associate) in HTML5 App Development Fundamentals
- Certified in Object Oriented Programming Using C#
- Certified in Developing Web Applications using ASP.NET
- Certified in C programming

EDUCATION

JUNE 2008 - MAY 2013

BACHELOR'S IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, GUJARAT TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY

- GPA of 7.3/10 overall
- Published a research paper at international level during final year project http://www.ijera.com/papers/Vol2 issue6/GJ2612891291.pdf
- Finalist in inter-college badminton tournament